<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FAQs on Piklist Documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FAQs on Piklist Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.piklist.com/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Piklist</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/what-is-piklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/what-is-piklist/</guid>
      <description>What is Piklist? Piklist is an incredibly powerful framework for WordPress. When using Piklist to enhance your WordPress themes or plugins, you will be able to build more powerful, flexible websites with less code. Just install Piklist as you would a normal WordPress plugin, and then start writing code in your theme or plugin. This website should help you get started and provide a quick reference.
Most people use Piklist to add fields in the WordPress admin area, but you can do a lot more with Piklist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I include Piklist in my plugin or theme?</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/how-to-include-piklist-in-plugin-or-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/how-to-include-piklist-in-plugin-or-theme/</guid>
      <description>While we understand why you may want to include Piklist in your plugin or theme, we believe it may negatively impact your users’ experience. Piklist is not a boilerplate framework and is always designed to be a standalone plugin. Piklist will not work properly if included in another plugin or theme.
If the user does install Piklist as a separate plugin, AND your plugin/theme, it invites multiple conflicts, including different versions of Piklist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why aren’t my fields saving?</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/fields-not-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/fields-not-saving/</guid>
      <description>The most common reason for fields not saving is because a post type uses the default WordPress “custom fields” meta box. This meta box actually duplicates the inputs used by your fields.
If you are registering a post type, make sure custom-fields is not in the “supports” array.
To remove the custom-fields meta box from a WordPress default post type, or one that is registered by another plugin, use remove_post_type_support().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a limit on the number of Piklist fields?</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/number-of-fields-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/number-of-fields-limit/</guid>
      <description>There is no limit to how many fields you can create and display with Piklist. However, your server limits how many can be used on each page.
This is not a Piklist issue&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s part of your servers configuration.
The most common solution is adjusting your max_vars setting. This is a PHP setting which sets the maximum variables that can be used in one page load.
Once you increase this limit, Piklist can finish rendering all it&amp;rsquo;s fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update script not running</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/update-script-not-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/update-script-not-running/</guid>
      <description>Piklist allows you to easily create update scripts that run on certain versions of your plugin. If the script doesn&amp;rsquo;t run, you may have an issue with the piklist_active_plugin_versions setting:
 Deactivate and delete Piklist Open your database. In the wp_options table, look for this field: piklist_active_plugin_versions and delete it. Reinstall piklist The piklist_active_plugin_versions should come back to your db. Log back into WordPress. The update script should run.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parse error: syntax error, unexpected T_FUNCTION</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/parse-error-syntax-error-unexpected-t_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/faq/parse-error-syntax-error-unexpected-t_function/</guid>
      <description>If you’re getting this error, you are running an older version of PHP on your server.
Piklist, like WordPress, recommends PHP v5.6 or higher.
Please contact your host and ask them to upgrade you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>