<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fields (General) on Piklist Documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fields (General) on Piklist Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 22:36:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionally Show Fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/conditionally-show-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/conditionally-show-fields/</guid>
      <description>Description Piklist makes it easy to show one or more fields, based on the value of another field, and so much more. The Piklist conditions parameter is very powerful, and you can see all the options in the documentation.
In this tutorial, if the user clicks on the “Yes” radio button to subscribe to our newsletter, we will show an “Email” text field.
 Conditional fields work on almost every page in WordPress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Menus as a Radio, Checkbox or Select list</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/display-menus-radio-checkbox-select-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/display-menus-radio-checkbox-select-list/</guid>
      <description>Description Using Piklist you can easily display your Menus as Radio, Checkboxes or a Select list (dropdowns). Easily include them in custom theme settings, or when creating posts. This simple tutorial will show you how.
  New to Piklist?    Before you start this tutorial:  Install Piklist like you would any other WordPress plugin. Decide if you are going to add the code in this tutorial to your custom plugin or your theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show Fields by User Capability or Role</title>
      <link>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/show-fields-user-capability-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.piklist.com/tutorials/fields/show-fields-user-capability-role/</guid>
      <description>With web applications and powerful websites, there will be times you want to only show a metabox or metafield to a particular user role or capability. For an Order Management system you may want your customers to see certain fields, while your employees can see them all. Or maybe you want Administrators and Editors to be able to leave notes on a post that no one else can see. Well, Piklist makes it easy to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>